# Ibrahim Oksuzoglu

Email: ibrahimhuseyin23@gmail.com |

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ibrahim-huseyin-oksuzoglu/

Portfolio: <a href="https://ibrahimoksuzoglu.netlify.app/">https://ibrahimoksuzoglu.netlify.app/</a> Phone: +44 7397 569553 | Location: London

#### **PROFILE**

Data Analyst and holder of a First-Class Honours BSc in Mathematics, with strong proficiency in Python, SQL, Excel, Power BI, VBA, MATLAB, and R. Applied analytical and statistical skills in both professional and personal settings. Completed machine learning projects focused on predictive modelling, clustering and sentiment analysis, enhancing practical experience with real-world datasets. Proven ability to solve complex numerical and abstract problems, supported by a solid mathematical foundation and a successful track record in data analysis.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Employed by FDM Group as an IT Consultant contracted to:

## Marks and Spencer - Data Analyst

July 2024 - Present

- Part of Data & Al Solutions Performing advanced statistical analysis, including A/B tests and hypothesis testing, to optimize product features, leading to data-driven decisions on new and existing products.
- Led ETL processes, ingesting and cleaning large datasets in Databricks using Python and PySpark to ensure data integrity and reliability.
- Implemented end-to-end data analysis solutions, transforming raw data into actionable insights that informed key product decisions, resulting in a value of £8 million in revenue saving.
- Created interactive visualizations and reports shared with stakeholders to drive business strategy.

# **Lloyds Banking Group - Data Analyst**

March 2023 - July 2024

- Spearheaded as the Lead analyst in the Data Quality team on the Single Customer View project conducting in depth data analysis on live Customer records.
- Utilized advanced SQL skills, writing efficient complex queries for data extraction and manipulation to match business records across multiple customer systems each containing 20,000+ customers to a master system.
- Demonstrated data management expertise, efficiently and accurately conducting data cleansing techniques using advanced Excel formulas for streamlined processes.
- Utilized stakeholder management and advanced Power BI skills to develop dynamic dashboards

## **Lloyds Banking Group - AML Analyst**

February 2022 - March 2023

- Conducted KYC remediation for 2000+ SME and non-SME customers, accurately assessing profiles and risk ratings.
- Researched and analyzed customer records with a 100% first-time pass rate, outperforming EY consultants.
- Escalated high-risk clients and identified potential adverse media cases, ensuring compliance

### **EDUCATION**

## **University of Surrey**

**September 2018 - July 2021** 

Bachelor of Science, Mathematics

- Grade: First-Class Honours
- **Relevant Modules**: General Linear Models, Experimental Design, Dynamic Asset Pricing Theory, Statistical methods financial applications, Numerical and Computational Methods, Real Analysis, Quantum Mechanics.

### **PERSONAL PROJECTS & SKILLS**

- Projects: K-means clustering, Regression, Data visualization
- Skills: Python, Pyspark, Excel, R, Machine Learning, SQL, Power BI, Databricks, Stakeholder Management
- Tools: Jira, Confluence, Miro